redbullmusicacademyradio.com 2017-08-20

# Privacy Policy | Red Bull Policy Center

## 1\. Introduction

1.1 This Red Bull Privacy Policy (" **Policy** ") sets out how Red Bull GmbH, whose registered offices are at Am Brunnen 1, 5330 Fuschl, Austria, (hereinafter “ **Red Bull** ”, " **we** ", " **us** ", " **our** ") collect and process information about you when you visit our website (" **Website** "). By continuing to use this Website, you consent to your information being processed in accordance with this Policy.

## 2\. Personal information we collect and how we use it

2.1 **Information you give us.** You may give us information, including information that can identify you (" **personal information** "), when you use our Website, correspond with us, or enter into any of our competitions, promotions or surveys. Where we request information from you, we will collect the information set out in the relevant forms or pages. You may choose to provide additional information to us when you contact us or otherwise interact with us.

2.2 If you are a regular user of our Website, you may wish to create an Account (" **Account** ") with us. The information that you provide when setting up your Account may include your name, email address and telephone number. If you register to hold an Account with us, you will also have a unique password which enables you to access your Account.

2.3 If you purchase any games, services, apps or other goods on our Website, we will also collect your delivery address, billing address and payment information. Please note that we will not be storing your payment information, this will be done via a third party payments company. If you subscribe to receive our newsletter, then you will provide us with your name, email address, gender and date of birth.

2.4 The personal information that you provide to us will be used for the purposes of enabling you to use our Website and making purchases via the Website, for administrative and troubleshooting purposes and in order to send you marketing materials (should you opt in to receiving marketing material from us). As explained in Section 2.8 below, we may also use this information for further purposes when combined with other data we collect about you.

2.5 **Information we collect automatically**. When you visit our Website, we may automatically collect the following information: your IP address, log-in information, location information, browser type and version, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform, information about your visit including the URL clickstream to, through and from our Website, products you viewed or searched for, download errors, length of visits to certain pages and page interaction. We collect information automatically through the use of various technologies, including through "cookies", and this is explained further below.

2.6 We use the information we collect automatically: (1) to administer our Website for internal operations including troubleshooting purposes; (2) to ensure that content from our Website is presented in the most effective manner for you and your devices; (3) as part of our effort to keep our Website safe and secure; (4) to measure or understand the effectiveness of advertising we serve to you and others, and to deliver relevant advertising to you; and (5) to make suggestions and recommendations to you and other users of our Website about goods or services that may interest you or them.

2.7 **Information we receive from other sources**. We may receive information about you if you use any of the other services we provide on this Website, or from other Red Bull entities and affiliates. We are also working closely with third parties (including, for example, business partners, sub-contractors in technical, payment and delivery services, advertising networks, analytics providers, search information providers, credit reference agencies) and may receive information about you from them (including information that is publicly available).

2.8 Where permitted by law, we may combine this information we receive from other sources, including from social media websites, with information you give to us and information we collect about you, including cookie information. We may use this information and the combined information for learning more about your preferences as our customer, for enhancing your user experience on our Website and for providing you with information, content and offerings tailored to your needs.

## 3\. How we share and disclose your information

3.1 We may share your information with our Red Bull affiliates for the purposes outlined in this Policy and with the third parties listed in this Policy. We may also share your information with third parties when: (1) it is necessary to involve a third party service provider in order to facilitate or extend our services; (2) explicitly requested by you (e.g. with social media networks); (3) required by a court order or any legal or regulatory requirement; (4) in connection with the sale or transfer of a business; (5) to enforce our Terms of Use; (6) to ensure the safety and security of our users, consumers and third parties; and (7) to protect our rights and property and the rights and property of our guests and third parties.

## 4\. How to opt in or opt out of direct marketing

4.1 We, and selected third parties, may use the information you give us on our Website for direct marketing purposes to provide updates; newsletters; events; or other communications that we think may interest you. Where required by law, your prior consent will be obtained before sending direct marketing. In any event, we will offer you the option to unsubscribe in every communication sent.

## 5\. Analysis and Advertising

5.1 We use third party tools, including the Turn Audience Suite and related tools provided by Turn to make the advertising we show you on our Website and/or our partner websites more relevant and interesting to you. For this purpose, we use cookies, web beacons or similar technologies to collect information about your browsing behaviour (see sections 2.5 and 2.6 above) and deliver interest-based ads to you. For further information about the use of data by Turn please click on the following link: http://www.turn.com/trust/privacy-guidelines. You may opt-out at any time from the collection and use of your data by Turn by clicking the following link: http://www.turn.com/trust/consumer-opt-out.

5.2 We also use third party tools, including Facebook Custom Audience and related tools provided by Facebook to provide advertising to you on other websites (including social media networks such as Facebook). Facebook Custom Audience is a tool provided by Facebook which matches a Red Bull customer/visitor with a Facebook user in order to provide advertising on the Facebook platform. For this purpose, we share your information with these third party providers (e.g. Facebook) and use cookies or similar technologies on our website to analyse the effectiveness of our advertising on other websites. For more information about the use of data by Facebook, please click on the following link: <https://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation>. You may withdraw your consent at any time from the use of your data for these purposes, by contacting us by email on [privacy@redbull.com](mailto:privacy@redbull.com).

## 6\. Cookies and other technologies

6.1 We collect information automatically through the use of "cookies". A cookie is a text file containing small amounts of information that a website can send to your browser, which may then be stored on your computer as a tag that distinguishes your computer but does not name you. Some of our Website pages use cookies to better serve you when you return to the Website. You can set your browser to notify you before you receive a cookie, giving you the chance to decide whether to accept it. You can also set your browser to turn off cookies; however, if you do this, some of our Website may not work properly.

6.2 For information about the specific cookies used on this Website, please refer to our Cookies Policy.

## 7\. Links to other websites and social media

7.1 Where we provide links to other websites, we do so for information purposes only. The other websites are outside our control and are not covered by this Policy. If you access other websites using the links provided, the operators of these websites may collect information from you which will be used by them in accordance with their privacy policy, which may differ from ours.

7.2 On some pages of our Website, third parties that provide content, applications or plug-ins through our Website may track your use of content, applications and plug-ins or customize content, applications and plug-ins for you. For example, when you share an article using a social media sharing button on our Website (e.g., Facebook, Twitter, or Google Plus), the social network that has created the button will record that you have done this. For more information on social media plug-ins on our Website, see our Cookies Policy.

## 8\. Data Retention

8.1 We will not retain your information for longer than is necessary for our business purposes or for legal requirements. However, please be advised that we may retain some information after you have closed your Account with us, for instance if doing so is necessary to meet our legal obligations, such as retaining the information for tax and accounting purposes.

## 9\. Your Rights

9.1 If you wish to obtain a copy of personal information that we hold about you, please contact us at the address below. Before responding to your request, we may ask you to verify your identity and to provide further details about your request. We will endeavour to respond within an appropriate timeframe and, in any event, within any timescales required by law.

9.2 If you have chosen to have an Account then you can access the personal information we hold about you via your Account to obtain a copy of it and to correct, amend, or delete information that is inaccurate. You can also close your Account at any time.

9.3 It is your responsibility to ensure that you submit true, accurate and complete information to your Account and keep it up to date. You may also update your personal information by contacting us, using the contact details provided below. Please make sure to include your name, username and post code in your initial correspondence; this helps us protect the details and preferences on your Account from unauthorised access.

## 10\. Information Security

10.1 We apply appropriate security measures to protect your personal information that is under our control from unauthorised access, collection, use, disclosure, copying, modification or disposal. All information you provide to us is stored on secure servers.

10.2 Where you have a password, which enables you to access our Website, you are responsible for keeping this password secure and confidential.

## 11\. Internet-based Transfers

11.1 Given that the Internet is a global environment, using the Internet to collect and process personal information necessarily involves the transmission of data on an international basis. While we generally store all of the personal information that we collect about you through our Website in your region (for example for European visitors, in the European Economic Area), it is possible that your personal information will be transmitted to parties outside your region (where data protection laws may be different). If such transfer happens, we ensure that it takes place in compliance with contractual or other measures to protect the information.

## 12\. Use of this Website by Minors

12.1 If you are aged 14 or under, please get your parent's/guardian's permission before you provide information to us via our Website. Users without this consent are not allowed to provide us with information and, in the event that they do so, we will cease to process their information as soon as we find out.

## 13\. Changes to the Policy

13.1 This Policy was last updated on 21.12.2016. A notice will be posted on our Website home page for 30 days whenever this Policy is changed in a material way. By continuing to use our Website you confirm your acceptance of the relevant changes.

## 14\. Questions about this Policy

14.1 This Website is maintained by Red Bull GmbH. If you have a question, concern or complaint about this Policy or our handling of your information, you can contact us by email on [privacy@redbull.com](mailto:privacy@redbull.com).
